Guide to the Preservation Pittsburgh Records, 1985-2005 AIS.2005.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Preservation Pittsburgh Records
1985-2005
1991-1998
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Preservation Pittsburgh
AIS.2005.03
7.25 Linear Feet (plus 3 cassette tapes and plaque)
These records contain documents collected by Mary J. Paradise, founding president of Preservation Pittsburgh, a nonprofit organization devoted to the retention and creation of designated historic districts and buildings within the City of Pittsburgh. The records span 1985-2005 and consist of general correspondence of the organization, meeting minutes, bylaws, committees, reports, research, and specific projects that Preservation Pittsburgh undertook.
History
Founded by Mary J. Paradise in 1991, the nonprofit organization, Preservation Pittsburgh, was born out of an unsuccessful, although very significant, attempt to prevent the demolition of an Oakland landmark: the Syria Mosque. A performance venue located on the corner of Fifth Avenue and Bigalow Boulevard in Oakland, the Syria Mosque was designed by Huehl, Schmidt & Holmes architectural firm of Chicago and constructed in 1912. As part of an official Master Plan, the University of Pittsburgh successfully lobbied (although perhaps illegitimately) the Pittsburgh City Planning Commission to raze the Syria Mosque to make way for an expansion of its medical facilities. Preservation Pittsburgh emerged out of the mobilization of concerned citizens in a very public protest and campaign known as the "Save the Syria Mosque Organization." Despite attempts by the Pittsburgh City Council to preserve the building, the Syria Mosque was torn down beginning in August 1991; today the site contains a parking lot.
This mobilization effort gave birth to Preservation Pittsburgh, which soon developed into a viable activist group with an advanced structure of bylaws, officers, a vast membership, and numerous committees in place, each with a prerogative concerning the retention and creation of designated historic landmarks, buildings, and districts. The organization's mission statement advocates for public awareness of local history and preservation, as well as the promotion of relevant goals to public officials, most notably the City Council. It has functioned to mitigate and instigate deliberations between government and development institutions, private groups, and citizen organizations in favor of its mission. It also has financially supported the creation and restoration of endangered historic landmarks, primarily buildings. Significant successful campaigns include the designation and restoration of Schenley Farms as a historic district as well as the Oakland Civic Center. Preservation Pittsburgh also supported the designation of the King Estate as a historic landmark, and other nineteenth-century mansions such as the former Victoria Hall, now the Waldorf School. Ascetic projects were also successfully undertaken to ban excessive billboard signs by recommending stringent regulations to the Pittsburgh City Planning Commission.
Scope and Content Notes
The Preservation Pittsburgh Records retained by Mary J. Paradise (founder) contain original drafts as well as final copies of correspondence, key contacts of influence, and institutional records such as committee reports, grants allocated by the city, membership lists, project files, meeting minutes, bylaws, composed document histories, newspaper clippings, and research. The bulk of the material dates from 1991, when Preservation Pittsburgh was officially formed, to 1998.
Arrangement
The records are arranged into the following three series:
Series I. Committee to Save the Syria Mosque, 1991-1995
Series II. Administrative Files, 1992-1999
Series III. Project and Relevant Organization Files, 1981-1998
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Previous Citation
Preservation Pittsburgh Records, 1985-2005, AIS.2005.03, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Historic buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh -- Conservation and restoration; Historic preservation -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Buildings, structures, etc.; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Historic districts -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Historic buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Administrative records; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Conservation and restoration; Nonprofit organizations -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Correspondence; Photographs; Minutes (Administrative records); Bylaws (Administrative records); Associations; Architecture; Preservation Pittsburgh; Syria Mosque (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pittsburgh (Pa.). City Planning Commission
- Committee to Save the Syria Mosque, 1987-1995; 1991-1992; I.
  - Chronology of the Syria Mosque events organized by Mary Paradise, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Historic Review Commission chronology & other reports by history organizations, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Historic Review Commission, minutes and reports, research for pending Alleghany County Court case, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Research for litigation to save the Syria Mosque, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Historic Review Commission, research material, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A History in Documents, Syria Mosque, Schenley Farms, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
  - The Syria Mosque & University of Pittsburgh, Newspaper Coverage & Letters, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - City Planning Commission, Historic Review Commission, research material, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Syria Mosque legal correspondence and fees, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Planning litigation to save the Syria Mosque, research & correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Historic Review Commission, clarification points, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Syria Mosque Advocacy planning, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Protest letters, meeting for Oakland hosted by the City Planning Commission, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper coverage, editorials, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence to Norman C. Arbes, Bureau for Historic Preservation, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Save Syria Mosque presentation to Commissioners of City Planning, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Protest letters, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jim Ferlo to Jack Paradise, how to designate a historic district or landmark, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Allegheny County Court of Pleas case, Committee to Save the Syria Mosque v. National Development Corporation et al, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Syria Mosque, research and correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Mass advocacy mailing, Save the Syria Mosque Committee, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Assorted Chronology, Syria Mosque, Schenley Farms Historic District, Oakland Civic Center, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Syria Mosque, research & correspondence, City Planning Commission, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Syria Mosque, research & correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Save the Syria Mosque, John G. Ranges, Chief of Chambers Development Company, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Syria Mosque, University of Pittsburgh Board of Trustees, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Syria Mosque, research & correspondence, University of Pittsburgh, Commission of City Planning, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Protest Photographs, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ferlo proposal to the City Planning Commission, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Committee to Save the Syria Mosque argues for designated historic landmark, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Save the Syria Mosque media, Preservation Pittsburgh unofficially formed, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh organized, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Supreme Court of Pennsylvania favors Mosque supporters, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Advocacy, outreach, Preservation Pittsburgh mission, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Designation of the Syria Mosque site, Preservation Pittsburgh, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - University of Pittsburgh Facilities Management Memorandum, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Petition to "Save the Syria Mosque", 1991 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Historic Review Commission, BOCA, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - City Planning Commission Syria Mosque recommendations and public hearing notes, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Civil suit records of Committee to Save the Syria Mosque v. National Development Corp., Syria Temple Holding Corp., Bureau of Building Inspection, and the City of Pittsburgh, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and legal records relating to Syria Mosque demolition protest arrests of James Ferlo, Marshall Goodwin, John Murdoch, and Albert Petracca, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence relating to the Syria Mosque and Oakland Civic Center Historic District, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Court of Common Pleas Appeal: Presbyterian University Health Systems, Inc. and National Development Corporation v. The City Council of the City of Pittsburgh and The City of Pittsburgh No. S.A. 2902-1991, ADD (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Historic Review Commission meeting minutes, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Save the Syria Mosque" Flier, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "The Significance of Historic Preservation in the Life of a Community, with Special Reference to the Syria Mosque and Oakland Civic Center" Final Copy and Draft, Roy Lubove, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Testimony to City Planning Commission and Historic Review Commission on Syria Mosque site, Roy Lubove, 1991; ADD (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Drafts of "Syria Mosque Chronology," Mary J. Paradise, 1991-1992; ADD (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Press relating to the demolition of the Syria Mosque, 1991-1992; ADD (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Position Papers and Statements for Syria Mosque Site and Oakland Civic Center, 1991-1996; ADD (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Press relating to Syria Mosque Site, 1991-1996; ADD (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Michael Eversmeyer HRC Historic Preservation Planner "Dear Interested Citizen" letters, Syria Mosque and Oakland Civic Center, 1991-1997; ADD (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Handwritten notes from City Council Meeting, March 12, 1992; ADD (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Settlement agreement between the City of Pittsburgh, the Council of the City of Pittsburgh, Presbyterian University Health Systems, Inc. and the National Development Corporation regarding the Syria Mosque Site, 1992; ADD (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence relating to Syria Mosque Site fence, 1995; ADD (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Later press coverage of Syria Mosque and Oakland preservation, 1995-2001; ADD (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence and attached reports relating to the Inclusion of Syria Mosque site in Oakland Civic Center Historic District, 1996; ADD (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Syria Mosque, legal research on historic preservation, undated; ADD (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Administrative Files, 1991-1999; 1991-1996; II.
  - Accomplishment evidence, 1992-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - ACLU, Legal and Organization Bylaws, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Action Planning, Preservation Pittsburgh, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Administration Binder, Paradise, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Administration assorted files, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Administration assorted files, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Advocate," Preservation Pittsburgh Newsletter, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "The Advocate," notes, assorted mailings, newspaper coverage, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Annual Award, the Jamie D. Van Trump Award, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Annual Award, James D. Van Trump, Jim Ferlo, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, Second, Goals established, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, Third, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, Victoria Hall, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Annual Reports, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Annual Reports, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Articles of Incorporation, Original bylaws, consultation, tax exemptions, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Articles of Incorporation, Internal Revenue Services, Bylaws, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Board of Directors, Preservation Pittsburgh, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Budget & Reports, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Bylaws drafting, 501-C-4, Add Hoc Committee, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bylaws drafting & reform, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Bylaws drafting & 501-C-3, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Bylaws 501-C-3 Taskforce, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Committee, Action Alert, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Committee, Architectural Assessment, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Committee, Environmental Amenity, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Committee, Finance, records & reports, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Committee, Membership, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Committee, Nominating, officer records, 1992-1996 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Committee, Officers, reports, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Committee, Public Relations, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Committee, Religious Structures, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Committee, Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - City Council, Correspondence & statements, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - City Council, Lobbying, correspondence, planning, grants, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - City Council President, Jim Ferlo, correspondence, lobbying, grants, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - City Council, Hearings of interest, 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Consultation work for Preservation Pittsburgh, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, Assorted, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, Assorted, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence, Significant mailing materials, documents--arranged by Paradise, 1993-1999 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Coverage in newspaper media, Preservation Pittsburgh early organization, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Chronology, Assorted by Paradise, 1991-1998 (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Early Organizing and Membership, 1991-1992 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Editor, Letters, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Formalizing Preservation Pittsburgh's Committe structure and bylaws, 1992-1995 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Garden Party Fundraiser, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Grants, Research materials, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Grants, Pittsburgh City Council, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grants, Pittsburgh Department of City Planning, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Grants, Pittsburgh City Council, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Grants, Pittsburgh Granting Agency, accomplishment representation, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Grants, Research into potential funding, 1991-1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Historical Architecture Review Board, Senate Bill No. 805 to protect private property, preservation of cities, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Historical Architecture Review Board workshop, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Internships, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Internal Revenue, 501-c-4, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Inventory, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lubetz, Arthur, Agreement expires, office moves to Cultural Trust Shared Office Space (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Lubetz, Arthur, Gift of office space, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Membership, Correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Membership, Early organizing, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Membership, Fundraising, treasurer's report, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Membership, Renewal sample letters, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Mailings & Postage, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
  - Meeting Announcements, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Meetings, Board, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Meeting Minutes, Board of Directors, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Meeting Minutes, Preservation Pittsburgh Handbook, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Meeting Minutes, annotated, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 35-36)
  - Meeting Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Meeting Minutes & Member Information, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Meeting Minutes & Membership, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Meeting Minutes & Membership, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Meeting Minutes, General Members, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Newspaper coverage media, correspondence & reports with members, University of Pittsburgh development in Oakland, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Historic Preservation Ordinance, Appeal to Councilman Ferlo, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Paradise, Assorted notes, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Paradise, Research information into nonprofit organization, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Pittsburgh City Parks, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Pittsburgh Register of Historic Places, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh, Initial organization as nonprofit, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh, Established as nonprofit, justification & planning, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh, Assorted board correspondence, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh, Initiatives, 1991-1994 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh, Original notes on possible goals & structure, 1985-1993 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Preservation Month, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Preservation Week, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Preservation Week, includes Pittsburgh City Council Resolution plaque, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12, Box 6)
  - Preservation Week, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
  - Preservation Week, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Preservation Week, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Preservation Week, Membership, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Preservation Week, Sunny Ledge Mansion, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Press Releases, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Promotional & Fundraising Events, 1992-1996 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Reports, Drafts, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Retreat, Preservation Pittsburgh, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Retreat, Meeting announcements, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Smithdale, Nancy--applicant for coordination consultant, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Action alerts, 1995-1996 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Advocacy Committee, Notes, Correspondence, and Legislation, 2008-2009 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Advocacy Network, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "The Advocate" Newsletter, 1994-2001 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Annual Dinner Meeting, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meeting and Awards Celebration, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Articles of interest, 1991-1997 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Awards and Recognition, 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Awards Nomination Files and Previous Awards, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, committee, and subcommittee meeting minutes and agendas, 1991-2001 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - By-Laws, Drafts, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - By-Laws, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - City Council meeting notes, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Compiled Press, 1989-2017 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Comprehensive Historic Preservation Plan, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Comprehensive Preservation Plan, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Email newsletter, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Financial files, Treasurer's Reports and invoices, 1994-2007 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - General Preservation Press, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Heritage Partnerships Presevation Conference, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Heritage Partnerships Preservation Conference and newsletters, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Historic Review Commission, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Incoming memos, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Internships, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Job Description Form, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - John Murdoch, Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - John Murdoch, News Clippings and Research, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Meeting Agendas and Committee Assignments, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 2008-2010 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Mission Statement, Brochure, Related Articles, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - News Clippings, 1997-1999 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Newsletter Information, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Notes from Networking Meetings, 2007-2008 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Office Files, Correspondence, 1993-2001 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Office Files, Press Releases, position statements, lectures, and public testimony, 1989-2001 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Office Files, Releases and action alerts from other preservation organizations, 1993-1998 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Ordinance, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Ordinance revisions, 1991-1996 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Pittsburgh Cultural Trust, Wood Street Office Space, 1995-1997 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Preservation Action Alert election newsletter, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Preservation advocacy, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Preservation Pennsylvania Newsletters and Brochures, 1992-1994 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Preservation Pittsburgh Library Project, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Preservation Related Organizations, 1992-1996 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Preservation Tax Credit Legislation, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - Preservation Week, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Preservation Week, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Preservation Week, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Press, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Press, 1998-1999 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Project ideas, 1996-1997 (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Sacred Places Committee Report, 2009 (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Strategic Planning, Organizational Strucutre and Priorities, 1992-1999 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Strategic Plan presentation, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Third Annual Dinner Meeting, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 61)
- Project and Relevant Organization Files, 1981-1998; 1992-1998; III.
  - Allegheny City Society, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Allegheny County Jail, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Allegheny Historic Preservation Society, Inc., 1993 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Begler Kowall & Ombres Law offices, Arthur Lubetz grant of office use, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Bigalow Boulevard, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Billboards, Pittsburgh campaign against, Public hearing 987.01 and 987.02 proposal to amend, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Billboards, Signs Zoning, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Billboards, Signs Zoning, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Billboards, Signs Zoning, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Billboards, Scenic America against, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Bloomfield Citizens' Council, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Bloomfield Garden Corporation, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Bridges, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Center Avenue YMCA, Manchester Citizens' group Executive Director, Rhonda Brandon supports Preservation Pittsburgh's dedication, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Center Avenue YMCA, National Trust for Historic Preservation president advocates, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Citizens' League of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Community Technical Assistance Center, 1985-1994 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Concept Paper: "Faith, Spirit, and Heritage: Houses of Worship in Western Pennsylvania," prepared for Preservation Pittsburgh president Arthur Lubetz, June 24, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - DeAngelis, Jim, Associate Professor, University of Pittsburgh, Urban and Regional Planning, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Downtown Pittsburgh, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Downtown Register Historic District Research, 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 46)